Harold Weston Papers
Harold Weston Papers
1897-1971
Weston, Harold, 1894-1972.
14.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American painter, humanitarian. The collection includes artwork reproductions, correspondence subject files, memorabilia and writings, much of which deal with Weston's work in various organizations, including the Adirondack Trail Improvement Society, the American Federation of Arts, the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, Food for Freedom, the International Association of the Plastic Arts of Plastic Arts, the National Council on the Arts and Government and the United Nations. The collection provides a detailed look at the lobbying efforts to create the National Endowment for the Arts as well as development of post-World War Two international cooperation in the arts.
149324
Biographical History
Harold Weston (1894-1972) was an American modernist painter and activist for humanitarian causes as well as international cooperation in the arts. Following his 1916 magna cum laude Fine Arts degree from Harvard, he built a log cabin near St Huberts, NY in the Adirondack Mountains where he became involved in the Adirondack Trail Improvement Society. Between the World Wars he travelled extensively in Europe and when the Second World War began, he founded Food for Freedom to deliver humanitarian aid to refugees. At the end of the War, Weston became involved in the creation of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) and through his work there, with the International Association of the Plastic Arts. His work on international arts cooperation in turn led him to lobby for government funding of the arts and the creation of the National Endowment for the Arts. Harold Weston died in New York City in 1972.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Harold Weston Papers consists of Artwork reproductions, Correspondence-subject files, Memorabilia and Writings.
Artwork reproductions includes more the two hundred black and white photographs of Weston's paintings with titles and dates.
Correspondence-subject files includes incoming and outgoing correspondence with a wide range of legislators, colleagues and public figures as well as the organizational records of various organizations in which Weston was involved, including the Adirondack Trail Improvement Society, the American Federation of Arts, the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, Food for Freedom, the International Association of Plastic Arts, the National Council on the Arts and Government and the United Nations, especially UNESCO.
Memorabilia includes newspaper clippings, several hundred photographs from Weston's travels around the world, especially to Iran, Iraq and India, aswell as exhibition catalogs and announcements.
Writings includes articles, several drafts of his book Battle of Bread and the texts of several speeches.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically by topic or title except for the general correspondence which is chronological.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Abbott, Berenice, 1898-1991.; Aiken, George D. (George David), 1892-1984.; Ailey, Alvin.; Albert, Carl Bert, 1908-2000.; Aldrich, Nelson W. (Nelson Wilmarth), 1841-1915.; Anderson, Marian, 1897-1993.; Andrews, Glenn, 1909-2008.; Anfuso, Victor L., 1905-1966.; Aspinall, Wayne N.; Avedon, Richard.; Avery, William Henry, 1911-2009.; Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981.; Bellamy, Ralph, 1904-1991.; Belluschi, Pietro, 1899-1994.; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990.; Blake, Eugene Carson, 1906-1985.; Bolling, Richard, 1916-1991.; Botkin, Henry Albert, 1896-1983.; Bowles, Chester, 1901-1986.; Boyd-Orr, John Boyd Orr, Baron, 1880-1971.; Brown, Clarence J., 1893-1965.; Buckley, Charles A. (Charles Anthony), 1890-1967.; Bunch, Ralph, 1927-; Burleson, Omar Truman, 1906-1991.; Byrd, Harry F. (Harry Flood), 1887-1966.; Cannon, Clarence, 1879-1964.; Carey, Hugh L.; Cater, Harold Dean, 1908-; Celler, Emanuel, 1888-1981.; Chavez, Dennis, 1888-1962.; Chayefsky, Paddy, 1923-1981.; Childs, Marquis W. (Marquis William), 1903-1990.; Clark, Joseph S.; Cliburn, Van, 1934-2013.; Collingwood, Charles.; Connally, Tom, 1877-1963.; Cooper, John Sherman, 1901-1991.; Cornell, Katharine, 1893-1974.; Crisp, Arthur, 1881-1974.; Curtis, Laurence.; Curtis, Thomas B. (Thomas Bradford),1911-1993.; De Mille, Agnes.; Dominick, Peter H. (Peter Hoyt), 1915-1981.; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976.; Dreyfuss, Henry, 1904-1972.; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Elliott, Carl, 1913-1999.; Ellsworth, Harris, 1899-1986.; Farbstein, Leonard.; Farrell, James T. (James Thomas); Flemming, Arthur S. (Arthur Sherwood) 1905-1996.; Fulbright, J. William (James William), 1905-1995.; Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1908-2006.; Garroway, Dave, 1913-1982.; Gellert, Hugo, 1892-1985.; Gish, Lillian, 1893-1993.; Herter, Christian Archibald, 1895-1966.; Holbrook, Hal.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Ives, Irving McNeil, 1896-1962.; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Hayden, Carl Trumbull, 1877-1972.; Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993.; Johnson, Lady Bird, 1912-2007.; Kearns, Carroll D.; Keating, Kenneth B. (Kenneth Barnard), 1900-1975.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Keogh, Eugene J. (Eugene James), 1907-1989.; Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Lescaze, William, 1896-1969.; Lindsay, John V. (John Vliet); Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1902-1985.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; Metcalf, Lee, 1911-1978.; Murrow, Edward R.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.; Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-1994.; Pell, Claiborne, 1918-2009.; Reuss, Henry S.; Richardson, Elliot L., 1920-1999.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-1979.; Schlesinger, Arthur M. (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007.; Scott, Hugh.; Steichen, Edward, 1879-1973.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.; Thompson, Frank.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand), 1910-1991.; Weston, Harold, 1894-1972.; Adirondack Trail Improvement Society.; American Federation of Arts.; Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors.; Food for Freedom.; International Association of the Plastic Arts.; United Nations.; Painting,American -- 20th century.; Art and state.; Federal aid to the arts.; Humanitarianism.; Clippings (information artifacts); Manuscripts for publication.; Drafts (documents); Black-and-white negatives.; Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Minutes (administrative records); Photographs.; Reports.; Artists.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Harold Weston, 1964-1971.
Inventory
- Artwork, reproductions
  - Adam, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Amber necklace, undated (Box 1)
  - Ann, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Arena, 1939 (Box 1)
  - At camp, 1932 (Box 1)
  - At tea, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Atunement, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Back to the Sun, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Basic bath, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Betwen windows, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Big head, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Bittersweet, 1929 (Box 1)
  - The blue kimona, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Braiding hair, 1925-1934 (Box 1)
  - Bronze nude, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Building the UNited Nations series 1, 1949-1952 (Box 1)
  - Building the United Nations(transparencies), 1949-1952 (Box 1)
  - Butterfly, 1930 (Box 1)
  - By camp fire, 1948 (Box 1)
  - By fire, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Cabbage, 1927-1933 (Box 2)
  - Calla lilies, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Callie, undated (Box 2)
  - Candlelight, 1929 (Box 29)
  - Catalan grandmother, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Cats fighting, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Cats under stove, 1926 (Box 2)
  - Cerêt chapel, undated (Box 2)
  - Chopelle Pond, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Charlotte, 1929 (Box 2)
  - China closet at Prats, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Combing hair, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Coming from the sea, undated (Box 2)
  - Convalescent, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Corn field, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Corner of studio, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Courting, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Crouching (figure), 1929-1930 (Box 2)
  - Cyclamen, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Dancers, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Dancers at Giens, undated (Box 2)
  - Dr. Felix Adler, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Dr. Henry Sloane Coffin, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Don't believe it, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Door, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Doubt, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Dressing, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Duck & bath, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Dutch girl, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Embryonic, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Etching tray, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Eva, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Fertilizing the fields, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Forest floor, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Forest spring, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Frances, undated (Box 2)
  - French girl, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
  - Fresco baby, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Fruit bowl, undated (Box 2)
  - Getting ready for bed, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Getting up, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Giant in the moonlight, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Girl reading, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Girl with the green hat, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Going home, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Gothic nude, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Harmony, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Haystack Mountain, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Head on pillow, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Helping hand, undated (Box 2)
  - Horizons, undated (Box 2)
  - Hospital bed, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Houses Cerêt, 1929 (Box 2)
  - In the studio (self portrait), 1949 (Box 2)
  - The inlet, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Intimacy, 1927 (Box 2)
  - The jester, 1933 (Box 2)
  - John Dos Passos, 1933 (Box 2)
  - The kiss, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Kneeling, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Leon Trotsky, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Loneliness, 1929 (Box 2)
  - The lumberman, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Making auto bodies, undated (Box 2)
  - Making hats, undated (Box 2)
  - Man and nature, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Man who brings our "fagots" of wood, Lt. Martin, 1929 (Box 2)
  - March wind-New York, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Marja, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Mary Pawling, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Marya, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Melon, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Memory, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Mimosa, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Mother and child, 1929 (Box 2)
  - My father (S. Burns Weston), 1927 (Box 2)
  - My father (S. Burns Weston), 1932 (Box 2)
  - Nanna the farm hand, 1929 (Box 3)
  - The new stove, 1926 (Box 3)
  - New York apartment, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Next? (Rue de la Harpe), 1927 (Box 3)
  - Nita, 1927 (Box 3)
  - Nude, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Nude on green, 1934 (Box 3)
  - Nude on pillows, undated (Box 3)
  - Oak leaves, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Oil refining, undated (Box 3)
  - On studio bed, 1930-1931 (Box 3)
  - Papa, undated (Box 3)
  - Paris Left Bank, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Peasant head, 1926 (Box 3)
  - Philadelphia from north east, undated (Box 3)
  - Philadelphia from south west, undated (Box 3)
  - Pines and Boreas Range, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Pine by lake, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Pine cones, undated (Box 3)
  - Pom poms, 1927 (Box 3)
  - Portrait of James Clark, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Posing, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Pregnancy, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Pre-view, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Pride, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Prof. Adler, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Profile, 1931 (Box 3)
  - The puppet, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Pussywillows, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Pyrenees farm, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Ready for camp, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Reclining nude, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Reservations, 1928 (Box 3)
  - Resignation, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Restless, 1929 (Box 3)
  - St. Georgina, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Sawing wood, undated (Box 3)
  - School girl, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Seated nude, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Self portrait, 1922 (Box 3)
  - Self portrait, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Self portrait, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Silence, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Sleep, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Song of Solomon, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Starting braids, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Strands, undated (Box 3)
  - Sunburst, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Swoon song, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Syphon, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Terrace at Prats, undated (Box 3)
  - Textiles - hosiery, undated (Box 3)
  - Torso, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Tree trunk, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Two figures, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Underssing, 1926 (Box 3)
  - Virginity, 1927 (Box 3)
  - Waking, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Washing feet, 1927 (Box 3)
  - Wind on wheat, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Winter, undated (Box 3)
  - Winter Sun, 1929-1930 (Box 3)
  - Woman at rest, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Woman in red, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Woman in yellow, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Woman reclining, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Woman sleeping, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Woman with folded arms, undated (Box 3)
  - Yellow birch, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous - destroyed, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous untitled, 1928 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous untitled, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous untitled, undated (Box 29)
- Correspondence subject files
  - Biographical material, 1931-1962 (Box 4)
  - General correspondence, 1947-1965; undated; 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Abbott, Berenice, 1953; 1956 (Box 4)
  - Actors' Equity Association, 1953; 1965 (Box 4)
  - Adams, Sherman, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Adirondack Trail Improvement Society, 1897-1961; 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Adirondack Trail Improvement Society, 1962-1970; undated; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Aiken, George D., 1951; 1959, (Box 5)
  - Ailey, Alvin, 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - Albert, Carl, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Aldrich, Nelson W., 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - Allen, Leo E., 1956 (Box 5)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1955-1957 (Box 5)
  - American Federation of Labor, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Anderson, Marian, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Andrews, Glenn, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Anfuso, Victor L., 1961 (Box 5)
  - The Arden House Conference on Family Living, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Artists' Societies for National Defence, 1941 (Box 5)
  - Aspinal, Wayne, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - Avedon, Richard, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Avery, William H., 1962 (Box 5)
  - Bailey, Cleveland M., 1956 (Box 5)
  - Barber, Samuel, 1956-1957 (Box 5)
  - Barden, Graham A., 1955-1960 (Box 5)
  - Bell, Alfonzo, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Bellamy, Ralph, undated (Box 5)
  - Belluschi, Pietro, 1956-1965 (Box 5)
  - Bernhardt, C. Murray, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1957; 1961 (Box 5)
  - Billings, Henry, 1954-1958 (Box 5)
  - Blake, Eugene Carson, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Bolling, Richard, 1956-1957 (Box 5)
  - Botkin, Henry, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Bourdelle, Pierre, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Bowles, Chester, 1945-1963 (Box 5)
  - Boyd-Orr, John, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Brown, Clarence J., 1956 (Box 5)
  - Brunsdale, Clarence, Norman, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Buckley, Charles A., 1956-1960 (Box 5)
  - Bunch, Ralph, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Burckhardt, Rudolph, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Burleson, Omar, 1959; 1961 (Box 5)
  - Byrd, Harry Flood, Sr., 1959-1961 (Box 5)
  - Cannon, Clarence, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Carey, Hugh L. 1965 (Box 6)
  - Carlino, Joseph F., 1962 (Box 6)
  - Catan-Rose Institute of Art, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Cater, Harold Dean, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Celler, Emanuel, 1955-1963 (Box 6)
  - Chavez, Dennis, 1959-1961 (Box 6)
  - Chayefsky, Sidney Aaron “Paddy”, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Childs, Marquis W., 1946-1947; 1960 (Box 6)
  - Clark, Joseph S., 1961-1965 (Box 6)
  - Cliburn, Van, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Collingwood, Charles, 1956; 1964 (Box 6)
  - Comager, Henry, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Committee for International Cultural Exchange, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Committee of the Weston United Nations Paintings, 1949-1965 (Box 6)
  - Connally, Tom, 1950-1951 (Box 6)
  - Cook, Howard A., 1956 (Box 6)
  - Cooper, John Sherman, 1947-1962 (Box 6)
  - Copland, Aaron, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Cornell, Katherine, undated (Box 6)
  - Crisp, Arthur, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Curtis, Laurence, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Curtis, Thomas B., 1959 (Box 6)
  - Daniels, Dominick V., 1962 (Box 6)
  - Delaney, James J., 1957 (Box 6)
  - De Mille, Agnes George, 1956; 1965 (Box 6)
  - Dent, John H., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Dominick, Peter H., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Douglas, Paul H., 1956-1962 (Box 6)
  - Dreyfuss, Henry, 1957-1965 (Box 6)
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1955-1962 (Box 6)
  - Elliott, Carl, 1957-1960 (Box 6)
  - Ellsworth, Harris, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Essex County Committee to Defend America, 1940-1942 (Box 6)
  - Evans, Luther H., 1947; 1950 (Box 6)
  - Farbstein, Leonard, 1961; 1963 (Box 6)
  - Farrell, James T., 1957 (Box 6)
  - Federal Security Agency, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, 1937-1955; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, 1956-1966; undated; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Feininger, Lionel, 1954-1956 (Box 7)
  - Fleming, Arthur S., 1961 (Box 7)
  - Flynt, John J., Jr., 1963 (Box 7)
  - Fogarty, John, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Food for Freedom: General, 1942-1945; 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Food for Freedom: General, 1949-1950; 6 folders (Box 8)
  - Food for Freedom: General, undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Food for Freedom: Financial, ), 1942-1948; 6 folders (Box 9)
  - Forand, Aime J., 1959 (Box 10)
  - Fulbright, J. William, 1957-1963 (Box 10)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Garroway, Dave, 1958-1960 (Box 10)
  - Gellert, Hugo, 1962-1965 (Box 10)
  - General Federation of Women’s Clubs, 1964 (Box 10)
  - George, Walter F., 1956 (Box 10)
  - Gershwin, Ira, 1956; 1958 (Box 10)
  - Giamio, Robert, 1960-1963 (Box 10)
  - Gish, Lillian, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Goldberg, Arthur J., 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Graham, Martha, 1961-1965 (Box 10)
  - Green, Edith, 1957-1965 (Box 10)
  - Green Theodore F., 1960 (Box 10)
  - Guillon, Allen W., 1942 (Box 10)
  - Halpern, Seymour, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Hansen, Julia Butler, 1961 (Box 10)
  - Harlow, Bryce, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Harris, Oren, 1962-1963 (Box 10)
  - Hathaway, William D., 1965 (Box 10)
  - Hayden, Carl, 1961 (Box 10)
  - Hayes, Helen, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Hays, Wayne, 1961-1963 (Box 10)
  - Hennings, Thomas C., 1957-1959 (Box 10)
  - Herter, Christian, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Hill, Lister, 1956-1965 (Box 2)
  - Hillyer, Robert S., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Hirschfeld, Al, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Holbrook, Hal, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Holland, Elmer J., 1965 (Box 10)
  - Holm, Celeste, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Houseman, John, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1944 (Box 10)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1956-1966 (Box 10)
  - The Institute of International Education, 1956; 1958 (Box 10)
  - International Association of the Plastic Arts, general, 1952-1955; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - International Association of the Plastic Arts, general, 1956-1959; 5 folders (Box 11)
  - International Association of the Plastic Arts, general, 1960-1961; 5 folders (Box 12)
  - International Association of the Plastic Arts, general, 1962-1963; 5 folders (Box 13)
  - International Association of the Plastic Arts, general, 1963-1965; 8 folders (Box 14)
  - International Association of the Plastic Arts, general, undated; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - International Association of the Plastic Arts, financial, 1952-1965; undated (Box 15)
  - International Union for Child Welfare, 1950 (Box 16)
  - Ives, Irving M., 1951-1957 (Box 16)
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1955 (Box 16)
  - Jackson, R.G. A., undated (Box 16)
  - Javitz, Jacob K., 1957-1965 (Box 16)
  - Joelson, Charles S., 1962 (Box 16)
  - Johnson, Lady Bird, 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1957-1964 (Box 16)
  - Johnston, Olin D., 1962 (Box 16)
  - Jones, Robert E., 1957-1963 (Box 16)
  - Kearns, Carroll D., 1959-1961 (Box 16)
  - Keating, Kenneth B., 1959 (Box 16)
  - Kelley, Augustine B., 1955-1956 (Box 16)
  - Kennedy, Jacqueline, 1961-1963 (Box 16)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1961-1963 (Box 16)
  - Kent, Norman, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Keogh, Eugene J., 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - King, Carleton J., 1962-1965 (Box 16)
  - Knaths, Karl, 1953-1954 (Box 16)
  - Knauth Arnold W., 1942-1955 (Box 16)
  - Koussevitzky, Serge and Olga, 1957-1965 (Box 16)
  - Kroll, Leon, 1954-1955 (Box 16)
  - Kuchel, Thomas H., 1962 (Box 16)
  - Lahm, Renee, 1941 (Box 16)
  - Lancaster, Burt, 1957 (Box 16)
  - Lardera, Berto, 1954-1965; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Latham, Henry J., 1956 (Box 16)
  - Lawrence, David L., 1961 (Box 16)
  - Lehman, Herbert, 1953-1965 (Box 16)
  - Leinsdorf, Erich, 1965 (Box 16)
  - Lescaze, William, 1958-1962 (Box 17)
  - The Library of Congress, 1947-1964 (Box 17)
  - Lindsay, Howard, 1959-1964 (Box 17)
  - Lindsay, John V., 1959-1966 (Box 17)
  - Lippman, Walter, 1956 (Box 17)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1950 (Box 17)
  - Long, Edward V., 1962 (Box 17)
  - Luce, Clare Booth, 1946; 1961,; 1962 (Box 17)
  - Luce, Henry, 1957 (Box 17)
  - Macleish, Archibald, 1941-1942 (Box 17)
  - Madden, Ray J., 1957 (Box 17)
  - Magnuson, Warren, 1961 (Box 17)
  - Mankiewicz, Joseph L., 1956 (Box 17)
  - McClure, Stewart E., 1956-1965 (Box 17)
  - McConnell, Samuel K., 1957 (Box 17)
  - McDowell, Harris B., 1959-1962 (Box 17)
  - McGee, Gale W., 1960 (Box 17)
  - McGovern, George, 1957 (Box 17)
  - McNamara, Pat, 1958 (Box 17)
  - Metcalf, Lee, 1956-1957 (Box 17)
  - Mills, Wilbur D., 1959-1961 (Box 17)
  - Mink, Patsy T., 1965 (Box 17)
  - Minnow, Newton, 1961 (Box 17)
  - Mitchell, MacNeil, 1958-1964 (Box 17)
  - Monroney, Almer Stillwell “Mike”, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Moore, Henry, 1963 (Box 17)
  - Morgan, Thomas E., 1959-1961 (Box 17)
  - Morrow, Elizabeth, 1943-1950 (Box 17)
  - Morse, Wayne, 1961-1962 (Box 17)
  - Moses, Robert, 1955-1961 (Box 17)
  - Mumford, L. Quincy, 1957 (Box 17)
  - Murray, James E., 1956-1960 (Box 17)
  - Murrow, Edward R., 1956-1962 (Box 17)
  - National Broadcasting Company, Inc., 1961 (Box 17)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, general, 1953-1956; 4 folders (Box 17)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, general, 1957-1960; 6 folders (Box 18)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, general, 1960-1962; 6 folders (Box 19)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, general, 1962-1964; 5 folders (Box 20)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, general, 1965-1967; 6 folders (Box 21)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, general, undated; 4 folders (Box 22)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, financial, 1955-1965 (Box 22)
  - The National Cultural Center, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Nielson, William Allen, 1946 (Box 23)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1960 (Box 23)
  - O’Hara, James G., 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - O’Neill, Thomas P., 1956-1957 (Box 23)
  - Pasvolosky, Leo, 1942 (Box 23)
  - Pell, Claiborne, 1961-1965 (Box 23)
  - Perkins, Roswell B., 1956 (Box 23)
  - Peterdi, Gabor, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Phillips, Duncan, 1942-1960 (Box 23)
  - Pousette-Dart, Nathaniel, 1942 (Box 23)
  - Powell, Adam Clayton, 1962; 1965 (Box 23)
  - Pringle, Henry, 1948-1950 (Box 23)
  - Prouty, Winston L., 1965 (Box 23)
  - Pucinski, Roman C., 1965 (Box 23)
  - Pulitzer, Joseph, Jr., 1956 (Box 23)
  - Randolph, Jennings, 1960 (Box 23)
  - The Reconstruction Service Committee, 1942 (Box 23)
  - Reuss, Henry, 1957-1965 (Box 23)
  - Rhodes, John J., 1956 (Box 23)
  - Ribicoff, Abraham, 1960-1962 (Box 23)
  - Richards, James P., 1956 (Box 23)
  - Richardson, Elliot, 1957-1959 (Box 23)
  - Richmond, Isidore, 1957 (Box 23)
  - Roberts, Owen J., 1946 (Box 23)
  - Robinson, Edward G., 1957 (Box 23)
  - Rockefeller, David, 1962-1964 (Box 23)
  - Rockefeller, John D., III, 1965 (Box 23)
  - Rockefeller, Laurence, 1965 (Box 23)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1956-1966 (Box 23)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1942-1962 (Box 23)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1937 (Box 23)
  - Roosevelt, James, 1965 (Box 23)
  - Root, John Wellborn, Jr., 1956 (Box 23)
  - Rusk, Dean, 1962-1963 (Box 23)
  - Russell, Richard B., 1951 (Box 23)
  - Saarinen, Eero, 1957 (Box 23)
  - Salinger, Pierre, 1961 (Box 23)
  - Saltonstall, Leverette, 1951-1956 (Box 23)
  - Sandberg, Carl, 1956; 1965 (Box 23)
  - Scott, Hugh, 1956-1959 (Box 23)
  - Shanley, Bernard M., 1956 (Box 23)
  - Sickles, Carleton R., 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Sievers, W. David, 1962 (Box 23)
  - Simon, Caroline K., 1960 (Box 23)
  - Smith, H. Alexander, 1956-1957 (Box 23)
  - Smith, Howard W., 1956; 1962 (Box 23)
  - Smith, William A., 1963 (Box 23)
  - Staudinger, Hans, 1942 (Box 23)
  - Steichen, Edward, 1963-1966 (Box 23)
  - Stevenson, Adlai E., II, 1961-1963 (Box 23)
  - Stillwell, James A., 1947 (Box 23)